ELIANA MCCARTHY

6035527418 Miami, FL 33142

eliana.mccarthy@comcast.net

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Human resource professional with more than 10 years of responsible management of Human resources programs and initiatives. Subject matter expert in benefits administration, employee relations, performance management, organizational development, policy implementation, affirmative action and employment law compliance. Strong leader with proven problem solving and conflict resolution skills sought out by colleagues and managers as a trusted advisor, consultant and business partner.

SKILLS

Benefits and compensation management Deltek - Costpoint

Succession planning Organizational development

Talent management Conflict resolution

ADP Workforce Now

WORK HISTORY

Human Resources Manager • Arrow Security & Training LLC

Nashua, NH · August 2018 to Current

- Maintain work structure by updating job requirements and job descriptions for all positions.
- Conduct annual salary surveys and developed, analyzed and updated company's salary budget.
- Oversee all HR needs for over 150-employee operation across 5 locations.
- Administer benefits programs and other competitive data and prepared budgets.

Human Resources Generalist • Airmar Technology Corporation

Milford, NH · March 2018 to August 2018

- Managed the implementation of a new system that transformed the HR resources management organization.
- Provided human resource generalist guidance to managers and employees including talent management, payroll, FMLA, benefits, workers compensation, 401K and OSHA compliance.
- Reviewed job applications to identify, vet and recommend optimal candidates.
- Shadowed employees to determine an accurate description of the duties and skills required for each position.

Human Resources Specialist • Wire Belt Company of America

Londonderry, NH · November 2014 to March 2018

- Improved organizational filing systems for confidential employee records, resulting in improved accessibility and efficiency.
- Ensured planning, monitoring, and appraisal of employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees.
- Reviewed existing policies and procedures to make recommendations for enhancing work productivity, recruitment, hiring processes and talent management.
- Directed onboarding and training for over 10 new employees each year, keeping company operations smooth and production efficient with skilled candidates.
- Developed succession plans and promotion paths for all staff.
- Conducted company-wide town hall meetings to convey updates.

Administrative Officer • U.S. Navy

Londonderry, NH • February 2011 to November 2014

• Engineered complete reorganization of administrative department which resulted in 100% job efficiency.

- Effectively coordinated and oversaw personnel administration for 280+ sailors, including timely updates to supervisors and preparation of reports.
- Counseled personnel on pay, allowances, and entitlements, processing \$50,000+ in bonuses and managing budget of \$3,000+ for recreational events.
- Managed command performance evaluation report programs.

Administrative Assistant • U.S. Navy

Bronx, NY • February 2006 to February 2011

- Provided administrative services, including phone and email correspondence, making copies and managing incoming and outgoing mail and faxes.
- Uploaded 900+ military records to the Official Military Personnel File (OMPF) website during conversion to electronic service records.
- Organized files, and prepared business and social letters, forms, notices, directives and reports.
- Provided superior customer service in a fast-paced environment.

Human Resources Consultant • Servicios Temporales De Colombia Cartagena, Colombia • April 2001 to May 2004

- Provided human resources, recruiting and resource management services in a commercial consulting environment.
- Discussed all employment aspects with prospective employees, including expected tasks, compensation and policies, to promote clarity from day one.
- Conducted job analysis and job evaluations, resulting in quality job specifications.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts - Psychology • *Universidad De San Buenaventura* Cartagena, Colombia • 2000

Master of Arts - Human Resources Management • *American Public University System* Charles Town, WV • 2012

Master of Science – Industrial and Organizational Psychology • Southern New Hampshire University

Manchester, NH • 2017

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Introduced the first formal performance review program, creating a flexible and well-received tool used company-wide.
- Led implementation of new HRIS system for the organization, writing over 10 standard operating procedures and training more than 200 employees.

CERTIFICATIONS

Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM) certification: SHRM-CP